Guide to the Carl Aldo Marzani Papers TAM 154
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Writings, undated, 1957-1987
  - Composition notebook: George Orwell, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Orwell, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Orwell-Preface: Author's note, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Carl for Working Orwell, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Orwell: Beyond 1984- Chapter 10, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Thoughts: essay "Reagan, Orwell & Spain.", undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Orwell Part I & II (2nd draft?), undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Penultimate draft: Orwell, Man & Myth, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Orwell Outlines - Incorporate, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Orwell, Chapter 11: Is a Socialist Renascence Possible, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Orwell: 2nd Thoughts on James Burnham, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Prefix & Intro, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Orwell:Intro, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Orwell: Davidson's Corrections, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Orwell: References in text, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Spain, Orwell and The Cold War, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Orwell: handwritten notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Orwell: Old and New Intro., undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Orwell: Intro 18, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Orwell (misc), undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Beyond 1984: Chapters 6-11, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Orwell: Articles, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Orwell and Spain Part II, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Orwell, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Orwell: footnotes and references, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Orwell's flawed Analysis, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The Other Orwell - Last Draft (From Spain through the Cold War), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The Promise of Eurocommunism- Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Eurocommunism Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Eurocommunism Changes, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Promise of Eurocommunism: Larry Ho; Correspondence/Royalties, 1979-1981 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Promise of Eurocommunism: Critical Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Quarter Century, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Survivor, 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The Survivor (Clippings), 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - The Survivor (Czech television), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Truth and Propaganda, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Wounded Earth Correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Wounded Earth (Business), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - The Wounded Earth (Reviews), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Memories of McCarthyism: Family Dialogs in 3 Acts by Ricky Marzani, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Series V: Political Activities, 1960-1976
  This series principally documents Marzani's involvement with The Rabinowitz Foundation, which supported efforts for political change and radical scholarship. These papers show the type of projects being considered for grants. Marzani read the proposals, and acted as a judge.
  - Rabinowitz Foundation (Misc.), 1960-1964 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Series VI: Publishing: Cameron Associations, Marzani & Munsell, 1953-1970
  Scope and Contents note
  This series principally contains correspondence, and also some contracts, permissions, publicity and other business materials. The bulk of these alphabetically arranged files are for individual authors. The Liberty Book Club files occupy .5 linear feet.
  Principal correspondents are first, Angus Cameron, and second, Carl Marzani. Secretary's initials, AR = Athene Ryan. Prominent correspondents (individual folders unless otherwise noted) include: Herbert Aptheker, C.B. (Beanie) Baldwin, Cedric Belfrage, Alvah Bessie, Herbert Biberman, Harry Bridges, E. Berry Burgum, W.E.B. Du Bois, Barrows Dunham (see Pamphlet Press), Howard Fast, Royal France, Stefan Heym, Albert E. Kahn (see Starobin, other files), Ring Lardner, Jr., Doris Lessing (see "Foreign" - Michael Joseph), Walter Lowenfels, Albert Maltz, A.J. Muste, Carey McWilliams (see The Nation), Truman Nelson, Victor Perlo, Edwin B. Smith, Edgar Snow, Joseph R. Starobin, Anna Louise Strong, Harry Ward, Ella Winter.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abbe, George, 1953-1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Abelard-Schuman, Inc. (Henry Schuman), 1953-1958 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ades, Bernard, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Agents, 1954-1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Agrin, Gloria, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Alfred, Helen, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Allen, Charles, Jr (contract), 1963-1968 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Allen, Charles, Jr., 1953-1964 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Armbruster, Howard M., 1953 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1953-1956 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Anthology (correspondence), 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Anthology (misc), 1948-1954 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1954-1966 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker, Herbert (contract), 1955-1965 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Aptheker, Herbert (royalty figures), 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Arts, Sciences & Professions (NY Council of the), 1953 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - B (misc), 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bailey, Harry, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Baldwin, C.B. (Beanie), 1954 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Baran, Paul, 1957-1964 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, 1953-1958 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1957-1962 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Biberman, Herbert, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Blue Cross, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Co., 1956-1960 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Boffa, Giuseppe (correspondence & contract), 1959-1960 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Book Photographs, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Book Club Ads (Others), undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Books Ordered, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Book Review (misc), 1958 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Book Reports, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Boyer, Richard O., 1953-1958 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Boyer-Morais Contract, 1954-1969 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Boyer-Morais (royalty figures), 1958-1963 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Braden, Anne & Carl, 1957-1963 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Bridges, Harry, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Burgum, E. Berry, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - C (misc), 1960-1962 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Cahn, Bill, 1954-1957 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - California Quarterly Coastlines Literary Magazine, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Cameron Associates, 1953-1960 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Cameron - European Trip, 1959, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Christmas List, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Cohen, Prof. Robert S., 1957-1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Columbia University Press, 1956-1959 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Committee for Legislation in the National Interest, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Copyright Information, 1955-1963 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Coward-McCann, Inc., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Crown Publishers, 1957-1962 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Cuba, books to, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - D (misc), 1953-1962 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Daily Worker, 1955-1960 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Davidson, Basil, 1954-1957 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - DeCaux, Len, 1953-1965 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - DeVries, Lini M., 1953 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Dodd, Mead & Co., 1958-1968 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Donner, Frank, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Doubleday & Co., 1953-1962 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - DuBois, W.E.B., 1953-1961 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - DuBois' Birthday (90th - 1958), 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Dutton, E.P. & Co., 1957-1961 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - E (misc), 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Emspak, Julius, 1953-1957 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - (no folder), undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt, 1953-1955 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Farrar, Straus & Cudahy, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Fast, Howard, 1953-1957 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Faulkner, Stanley, 1955-1959 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Feinberg, Abraham L., 1965-1970 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Feldman, Eugene, 1956-1958 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Financial Contributors, 1953-1956 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Fitzgerald, Albert J., 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - France, Royal W., 1956-1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - France, Royal W. (contract), 1957 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Frantz, Laurent B., 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Freedman, David M., 1958 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Fried, Emmanuel J., 1953-1959 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Freedman, Burrill, 1953-1962 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Frontier Bookstore Book News, 1954-1956 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Frontier Magazine, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Foreign: Academiei Republici, Agenzia Letteraria, Agence Literaire, 1955-1957 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Foreign: Bookman Literary Agency, Bureau Hongroia, Bulgarian, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Foreign: Calder, John, 1956-1961 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Foreign: Jonathan Cape, 1955-1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Foreign: Central Books (London), Ceskoslovensky Spisovatel, 1953-1957 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Foreign: Clarte (Stockholm), Collets Book Store (London), Current Book House (Bombay)., 1955-1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Foreign: Collett's Holdings, 1953-1960 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Foreign: Das Neue Berlin, Andre Deutsch, Dietz Verlag, Domkfiazki, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Foreign: Melvin Durden, Dennis Dobson, Editori Riunite, Casa Editrice Einaudi, Edizioni di Cultura Sociale., 1956-1959 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Foreign: Encyclopedia Popular de Cuba, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Foreign: Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, Gondolat Kiado, Graphic Export Centra., 1954-1958 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Foreign: Foreign Language Press, Frederick Muller, Ltd., 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Foreign: Victor Gollancz (London), Volksverlag Weimar, 1955-1961 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Foreign: Robert Hale, Ltd., George C. Harap & Co., Harvill Press, Hillway Publishing Co., 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Foreign: International Affairs (Moscow), International Editors (Buenos Aires), Hope Leresche & Steele (London)., 1954-1962 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Foreign: Lavoro (Rome), Richard A. Law, Ludgate House (London), 1953-1956 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Foreign: Pearn, Pollinger (London), 1953-1958 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Foreign: Publishing House for Foreign Literature (Moscow), Routledge, & Kegan Paul Ltd, Rutten & Loening (Berlin)., 1954-1959 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Foreign: Seven Seas (DDR), Martin Secker & Warburg (London), undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Foreign: Michael Joseph Ltd (London) {incl Doris Lessing ltr}, 1953-1958 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Foreign: Seven Seas, Sidgwick & Jackson, Ltd (London), undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Foreign: Spoldzielnia Wydawnicza (Warsaw), 1953-1958 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Foreign: State Publishing House of Literature (Bucharest), 1961 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Foreign: Tavistock Publications (London), Tokyo Shuppan Hambai, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Foreign: Union of Writers (USSR), Verlag Der Nation (Berlin), 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Foreign: Lawrence & Wishart (London), 1953-1961 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Foreign: Zavod (Belgrade), Zeno (London), 1955-1958 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Foreign (Misc), 1958-1961 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Foreign Literary Agents, 1953-1957 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Foreign Publishers Lists, 1953-1955 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Foreign Rights - Allen, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Foreign Rights - Aptheker, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Foreign Rights - Belfrage, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Rights - Bessie, 1957-1959 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Foreign Rights - Boyer-Morais, 1954-1959 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Foreign Rights - Dunham, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Foreign Rights - France, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Foreign Rights - Frank, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Foreign Rights - Gillman, 1956-1959 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Foreign Rights - Lardner, 1954-1959 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Foreign Rights - Marzani, 1959-1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Rights - Matusow, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Rights - Merriam, 1956-1961 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Rights - Polonsky, 1957-1961 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Rights - Rickett, 1957-1960 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Rights - Somverville, 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Rights - Starobin, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Rights - Struik, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Rights - Voynich, 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Rights - Wexley, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - G, 1961-1963 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Garlin, Sender, 1953-1955 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Gillman, Joseph., 1955-1968 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Gillman, Joseph (contract), 1956-1968 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Glazier, William (ILWU), 1953-1955 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Gordon, Sydney, 1959-1966 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Gordon, Sara, 1954-1959 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Gourfain, Ed, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Gregorova, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Gropper (Paul Bunyan) - drawing, removed for trfr to NP, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - H, 1960-1964 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Hare, Nathan, 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Harlem Stirs, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1957-1962 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Harold Ober Associates (Ivan Von Auw), 1953-1959 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1958-1961 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Henry Regnery Company, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Heym, Stefan, 1957-1960 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Houghton MIfflin & Co., 1954-1962 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Hill & Wang, 1957-1964 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - I (misc), 1961 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - International Publishers, 1954-1958 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - J (misc), 1960 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Jefferson School of Social Science, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Jero Publishing Co. (re: Death House Letters of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg), 1954 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - John O'London's, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - J.W. Corporation, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Kahn, Albert E. (of Cameron & Kahn, publishers), 1953-1962 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Kahn, Arthur, 1953-1958 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., 1955-1959 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Koss, Harry (U.S. salesperson for Marzani), 1954-1965 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1953-1960 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - L (misc), 1961-1962 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Lardner, Ring Jr., 1953-1972 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Lardner, Ring Jr. (contract), 1954-1967 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Lardner, Ring Jr. (royalty figures), 1955-1959 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Lawson, John Howard, 1953-1957 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1953-1958 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Levy, Hyman, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - (no folder), undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Liberty Book Club - ads, proofs, etc., undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Liberty Book Club - board meetings, 1955-1960 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Liberty Book Club - list of selections, 1948-1964, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Liberty Book Club - financial, 1954-1960 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Liberty Book Club - forms, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Liberty Book Club - insurance, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Liberty Book Club - membership promotion, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Liberty Book Club - notes from Liberty Series & from National Guardian Ads, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Liberty Book Club - mailings, samples, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Liberty Book Club - mimeographed materials, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Liberty Book Club - old members list (i.e., letters), 1957 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Liberty Book Club - Record Club, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Liberty Book Club - Reports of Audit, 1949-1952 (Box MS002)
  - Liberty Book Club - renting agent, 1961-1964 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Little Brown & Co., 1953-1959 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Longmans Green & Co., 1955 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1953-1959 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Lubelski - manuscrip correspondence, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Lumberjack News, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - M (misc), 1960-1962 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Marzani-Peet (NATO book), 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Marzani & Perlo (Dollars and Sense of Disarmament), 1960-1961 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Marzani & Munsell - art work, etc., undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - MacDougall, Curtis (Gideon's Army), 1964-1967 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - MacMillan Company, 1956-1966 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Mainstream, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1953-1959 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Merger, 1955 (between Cameron & Kahn, Inc., Seller, and Cameron Associates, Inc., Buyer)., 1954-1958 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Merriam, Eve, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Statements & Publications, 1950-1959 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Mitchison, Naomi - contract & correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Monthly Review, 1956-1967 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Morais, Herbert M., 1953-1966 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Morris, Edita (The Flowers of Hiroshima), 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Munsell, Alex, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Muste, A.J., 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Myers, Beth (wife of Frederick "Blackie" Myers), 1954-1959 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - N (misc), 1957-1962 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - The Nation, 1954-1959 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - National Guardian, 1954-1961 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - National Guardian: Merger (proposed), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Negro Ministers and Newspapers, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Nelson, Truman, 1953-1959 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Nelson, Wallace, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Newberry, Mike, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - New Era Book Club, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Karl Niebyl (Florentine painting and it's social background), 1954 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - W.W. Norton & Company, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Oxford University Press, 1956-1964 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - P (misc), 1961-1965 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Paperbacks - production, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Paperback Book Club - preparatory material, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Perlo, Victor, 1953-1965 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Pamphlet Press, 1957-1958 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Petran, Tabitha, 1953-1955 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Polonsky, Abraham, 1956-1961 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Postal Information - Liberty Book Club, 1955-1966 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Powell, William, 1955-1957 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Promethean Review (Liberty Book Club), 1959-1961 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Promotional Materials, 1954-1965 (Box MS002)
  - Ptashne, Theodore, 1953-1956 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Public Relations: clippings, permissions, letters, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Public Relations: clippings, permissions, letters, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Publishers Weekly (Bowker), 1953-1956 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1955-1959 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - R (misc), 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Random House, 1958-1963 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Reuben, William A., 1953-1956 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Rickett, W. Allyn, 1956-1959 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Rickett - contract, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Rickett - royalty figure, 1957-1964 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - S (misc), 1959-1962 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Sachs, Bernard (The road from Sharpeville), 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Salk, Edwin (Bud), 1963-1968 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Shanghui, Ramesh (Indian Book Club), 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Scientific American, 1953-1958 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Schuman, Julian, 1956-1962 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Shields, James, 1953-1958 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Simon & Schuster, 1954-1962 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Slater, Montagu - contract, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Edwin B. (Am-Rus Literary and Music Agency), 1953-1959 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Snow, Edgar, 1963-1964 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sobell Committee, 1954-1956 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Somerville, John, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Somverville, John - contract, 1955-1960 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Spitzer, Benjamin L., 1954-1959 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Starobin, Joseph R. (Eyewitness in Indochina), 1954-1958 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Starobin, Joseph R. - royalty figures, 1954-1968 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Stevenson, Janet & Philip, 1953-1959 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1956-1960 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Struik, Dirk, 1956-1961 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Tank, Herb, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Terman, Mandel A., 1953-1958 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Terry, Bill, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - TV Party - Angus Cameron Appearance, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - U - V (misc), 1961-1964 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Union Contract (M&M with District 65, RWDSU), 1956-1967 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1956-1958 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Viking Press, 1956-1960 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - W (misc), 1960-1964 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Ward, Harry, 1956-1972 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Watts & Co., 1955-1962 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Wexley, John - contract, 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Wexley, John - royalty figures, 1956-1962 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Wilkerson, Doxey, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Williams, Robert, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Winter, Ella, 1957-1959 (Box 31, Folder 17)
- Series VII: Addendum, undated, 1942-1994
  This series consists principally of various writings, published and unpublished. About one-half of the series consists of copies of Marzani's columns for the Greek newspaper Ethnos, most written in the 1980s. There are also several unpublished plays, written while Marzani was in the army during World War II, and a typsecript describing an LSD experience. There is also FOIA correspondence with the FBI and the NYC Police Department. This series also holds FOIA files about the FBI's documentation of Marzani and additional articles and writings by and on Marzani.
  - Includes several plays written during WWII, undated (Box 32)
  - Includes LSD typescript, undated (Box 33)
  - Includes memorabilia., undated (Box 34)
  - Articles written for Ethnos [Greek newspaper], 1980s (Box 35)
  - Articles written for Ethnos [Greek newspaper], 1980s (Box 36)
  - Articles written for Ethnos [Greek newspaper], 1980s (Box 37)
  - Autobiographical Typescript, undated (Box 38)
  - FOIA correspondence - FBI, NYC Police Department, undated (Box 38)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - FOIA Files, 1942-1978 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Liberty-Prometheus Book Club, 1959-1980 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Reluctant Radical-Promotional Materials, 1990s (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Articles about Carl Marzani, 1971-1991 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Carl Marzani-Reviews of "Reluctant Radical", 1992-1994 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Articles by Carl Marzani, 1959-1987 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Carl Marzani-Obituaries, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Pamphlets by Marzani, Including "The Threat of American Neo-Fascism," "Withdraw! From an Indochina War that dishonors our Country and threatens Nuclear Disaster," and "Eugene J. McCarthy for President", undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
- Series VIII: Nonprint Materials, 1938-1990